His CIA code name is Condor. In the next seventy-two hours
almost everyone he trusts will try to kill him.
Three Days of the Condor is a thriller, mystery film directed by Sydney Pollack.
When bookish CIA researcher Joe Turner finds all his co-workers dead, he, together with a woman he has
kidnapped, must work together to outwit those responsible until he determines who he can really trust.
Joseph Turner, played by Robert Redford.
Kathy Hale, played by Faye Dunaway.
J. Higgins, played by Cliff Robertson.
G. Joubert, played by Max von Sydow.
Mr. Wabash, played by John Houseman.
Leonard Atwood, played by Addison Powell.
Three Days of the Condor is a 1975 American spy thriller film directed by Sydney Pollack and
starring Robert Redford, Faye Dunaway, Cliff Robertson, and Max von Sydow.
The screenplay by Lorenzo Semple Jr.
and David Rayfiel was based on the 1974 novel Six
Days of the Condor by James Grady.
Set mainly in New York City and Washington, D.C., the film is about a bookish CIA researcher who comes back from lunch one day to discover his
co-workers murdered, then subsequently tries to avoid his own murder and outwit those responsible and understand their motives.
The film was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Film Editing.
Semple and Rayfiel received an Edgar Award from the Mystery
Writers of America for Best Motion Picture Screenplay.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency
(cia), office, conspiracy, condor, christmas.
The tone is mind_bending and intense.